# Curriculum vitae

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

## Muthukumar Pandaram

- Apartment 130, Gotthardstr. 96, 13403 Berlin, Germany
- **(+49)** 15175552738
- mkumar1308@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/muthukumarpandaram/

#### **SUMMARY**

A versatile and analytical Master's student in Computational Neuroscience with over 2 years of research experience gained through working at different research labs across the world. Possess a Bachelor's in Mechanical Engineering with demonstrated skills in control, sensor interfacing and machine learning techniques. Passionate about working at the intersection of Neuroscience and AI.

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### 20 Oct 2020-current

## Master of Science – Computational Neuroscience

Technical University of Berlin, Berlin (Germany)

- CGPA: 1.65
- Deutschlandstipendium (German National Scholarship) recipient for the academic year 2020-21, awarded by BMBF, Germany and a private sponsor.

#### 21 Jul 2014-30 Apr 2019

## Bachelor of Engineering – Mechanical Engineering

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore (India)

- CGPA: 9.52/10 (Batch Topper and Gold Medallist)

# WORK EXPERIENCE 01 Nov 2022–Present

## Working Student

Manipulator Cluster, Gestalt Robotics, Berlin (Germany)

Creating a flexible bin picking solution for industrial automation.

### 19 Mar 2021-31 Oct 2022

# Student Research Assistant

Robotics and Biology Lab, Technical University of Berlin, Berlin (Germany)

- Working on a project funded by the Science of Intelligence excellence cluster under Prof. Dr. Oliver Brock
- Set up the control hardware for soft robotic hands using proportional valves and flow sensors built on ROS framework.

### 15 Nov 2019-31 May 2020

### Research Intern

Centre for Alternate Cooling Technologies, PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore (India)

- Worked on a Department of Science and Technology aided project.
- Developed an experimental apparatus for evaluating the performance of a Solar Assisted Liquid Desiccant based air-conditioning system.

## 13 May 2019-2 Aug 2019

## Undergraduate Research Intern

Robotics and Manufacturing Automation Lab, McMaster University, Hamilton (Canada)

- Was one of around 600 students from around the globe selected through the MITACS Globalink Research Internship Program.
- Modified a custom written open-source numerical solver in MATLAB and C++ for simulating the hyperelastic behaviour of soft pneumatic actuators.

#### 10 Dec 2018-15 Feb 2019

### Research Intern

Medical Mechatronics Lab, National University of Singapore, Singapore (Singapore)

- Developed thermo-mechanical finite element models in ANSYS which coupled the viscoelastic behaviour of hydrogels and the shape memory effect exhibited by nitinol wires.
- Interfaced a battery-less NFC based transponder platform to get data from analog sensors developed at the Singapore Institute of Neurotechnology (SINAPSE) through an Android app.

### 13 May 2018-28 Jul 2018

## Summer Research Fellow

Manufacturing Engineering Section, Indian Institute of Technology, Madras, Chennai (India)

- Was one of 20 Summer Fellowship students selected from across the country.
- Developed an algorithm for automated registration of design surfaces (in NURBS surface format) and the manufactured surfaces (reconstructed from 3D LASER scanned Point clouds) for inspection of free form surfaces.
- The proposed algorithm was around 10x faster than the commonly used Iterative Closest Point (ICP) algorithm. It was also independent of the initial orientation of the two surfaces.

### 15 May 2017-28 Jul 2017

### Research Intern

Surgical Technologies lab, University of Leeds, Leeds (United Kingdom)

 Developed a finite element model in ABAQUS to simulate the hyperelastic behaviour of a soft tactile sensor body and compared the different hyperelastic models.

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

# Mother tongue(s)

Tamil

Foreign language(s)

English (CEFR Level C1), German (CEFR Level A1)

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **Publication**

### Soft Tactile Sensors with Variable Compliance,

Shehran Azim, Abhinandan Srinivasan, **Muthukumar Pandaram**, Junwai Kow, Greg de Boer, Hongbo Wang, Ali Alazmani, Peter Culmer, IEEE Sensors, 2017

# Projects

- Neural Mechanisms of real world visual categorical decisions
  - Analysed EEG data to find when and where the decisions made based on visual perception take place in our brain.
- Motion planning for Autonomous Vehicles:
  - Developed a motion planning node using the Autoware.auto framework based on ROS2 and simulated the vehicle in LGSVL.
- Social Robots
  - Working on a project to find what socials skills make robots appear intelligent.

### Relevant Master's courses

Machine Intelligence, Robotics, Applications of Robotics and Autonomous systems

### **Technical Skills**

Languages Known: C, C++, Python, MATLAB

Middleware: ROS 1 and 2

CAD Modelling Packages: PTC Creo, SolidWorks

Simulation Packages: ANSYS Structural and FLUENT, ABAQUS CAE